I'm thinking Hooper is going to have the
advantage on speed and kicking and I
think that could be a deciding factor
here we have covered more unofficial
records in the buildup to the 2024
Sheffield than we ever have before it
did not look like it was a difficult
lift for him to go 2 and half kilos over
the current world record the top of the
bullet the Warhead if you will is like
half the weight and you actually have to
take it off if you want to drink coffee
out of
it hey folks welcome back to another
rousing episode of strength weekly we
have one of the heaviest strongest MMA
fights of all time we're previewing that
also maybe the world's heaviest coffee
mug almost definitely the world's
heaviest coffee mug hawor bjon preps his
return to Pro strongman and a new
unofficial bench press world record that
we might see officially fall in just a
few weeks in Great Britain but before we
get to that make sure you subscribe to
barbin on YouTube where we're bringing
you the best from all all around the
strength world I'm one of your Intrepid
co-hosts David Thomas to and your even
more intrepid co-host Phil bman well
he's joining me Phil how you feeling
today you feeling wide you feeling
strong you feeling pumped oh I'm feeling
wide I don't know if I'm feeling strong
but I'm definitely feeling pumped well
get pumped because everyone in our
rundown today is we have a very
strongman heavy very strongman heavy
episode that's fine that's fine we like
that Phil of these four stories which
are you most excited about and why is it
the first one we're talking about I'm
kidding you pick whatever you want if it
wasn't going to be Mitchell Hooper and
Eddie Hall just going to fisticuffs I
mean I'm I do love coffee on any other
day it's the coffee mug that I can't
lift but this time around it's got to be
Mitchell Hooper and Eddie Hall seeing
which guy they you know just throwing in
hands well we're gonna use that as a
segue because both these guys can lift
really heavy coffee mugs although I'm
not sure what their caffeine intake is
day today we'd have to double check with
him Mitchell Hooper the reigning world
strongest man who by all accounts is
going to try to defend his title this
year and is also competing at the Arnold
strongman classic in early March last we
heard he's actually fighting in his
first MMA match in February about a
month less than a month before he takes
a stage to compete strongman in Columbus
and not only is he fighting he's
fighting Eddie Hall who actually has
combat experience as a trained boxer
remember he fought and lost to H bson
but did train in boxing Eddie Hall
himself a world Strongest Man Champion
we also know that Brian Shaw is fighting
at this competition we don't know who
but Brian Shaw retired from Pro
strongman Mitchell Hooper currently a
pro
strongman and is taking is is stepping
to the ring against Eddie Hall just
weeks before he competes in
strongman what is going on you know I
mean Mitchell Hooper not only is
Mitchell Hooper the reigning world
strongest man he's also the reigning
Arnold strongman Champion so he's going
to go to Columbus to try and defend that
title as well two weeks after the after
uh throwing hands with Eddie Hall in the
Octagon for the first time now uh both
of these guys are stepping into the
Octagon for the first time so Eddie Hall
is used to punching but I don't know if
either of these guys are gonna you know
be throwing kicks and we know that calf
kicks can be pretty devastating in the
Octagon we know that uh Mitchell Hooper
has been uh getting some more or less
karate training to learn how to properly
kick he's getting some roundhouse kick
training to really put Eddie Hall down
now they're only going to go for a
couple of rounds at two minutes a piece
but they are very large men with not a
lot of if any actual fighting experience
and they are going to Cutter to compete
on February 17th in what we have been
told is for an insane amount of money
that hasn't been disclosed as like what
specifically that is but enough that
they're willing to fly to Cutter and
beat each other up two weeks before one
of the biggest contests of the year in
strongman so the prize purse has been
hinted at but not officially confirmed
and it's sort of like oh believe us
it's enough
money it's enough there's this OD thing
where it's like okay let's say it's in
the you know it's in the millions of
dollars or whatever as as like the total
prize p that's being split amongst
whatever whatever whatever and these
guys are bringing star power to this
event even if that's the case is the
fight going to be good like these guys
don't have any fight experience like if
anything it might just be like the
spectacle of the of two world's
strongest men just wailing on each other
that like that actually might be it well
I mean there's there's there's punching
obviously uh which Eddie Hall has some
experience with in his boxing training
there's grappling there's kicking and
the thing is like I actually think that
kicking might be one the most underrated
aspect this because like a shin kick
from a pro strongman is got a hit
different and in fact Mitchell Hooper
the
Canadian has been receiving training
Fort karate world champion black belon
Hall of Famer sylvana Shimon uh I think
I'm saying that right also Canadian and
they they posted a YouTube video
together where she's training him in
kicks now look gota be honest I don't
think we're going to see any spinning
roundhouse kicks to the face I don't
think we're gonna see that kind of
Mobility from these guys but here's my
prediction here's my prediction all
right Mitchell Hooper we have seen him
he's one of the most athletic open class
pro strong man in history right this
guy's out there doing bar muscle ups
moving fast doing barbell jerks like an
Olympic weightlifter dude is fast he's
mobile and he's he's like fairly long
I'm actually thinking he's got the
advantage here because I think he's
going to be able to keep Eddie Hall at
range with some with some kicks right
you're talking about calf kicks Shin
kicks like Eddie's a brawler we saw that
in his fight with hathor Bon he wants to
get close he wants to use he wants to
throw fistic cuffs but like I'm thinking
Hooper's gonna have the advantage on
speed and kicking and I think that could
be a deciding factor here I'll double
down with you I think Hooper has the
advantage in every way across the TA
down the tail of the tape he's got the
age Advantage what we know from uh Eddie
is when he trained in boxing he got hurt
in training that postponed that fight he
tore his bicep when we were doing H Thor
versus Eddie in the ring it was
everybody thought that Hall was going to
have a better performance because he's
the feistier fighter he's the more
aggressive guy Boron was always more uh
composed is what he ended up being more
composed yes he was the more he was the
more composed guy yeah yeah so it's like
we we thought that in in the boxing ring
at least that Eddie Hall was going to
bring that aggressive brawling style and
that was going to confound bjornson and
then take the win but that wasn't what
happened bjornson used better technique
and that's what got him the win over
Hall in the boxing ring and I expect to
see something pretty similar because if
we know anything about Hooper in the
strongman game it's that he is the most
precise and like methodic athlete in the
game like he's changed how other
athletes perform in strongman because of
how he how method IAL he is on certain
events and I expect him to just do that
exact same thing in the octagon and
really take it to Hall so if I were a
bet man which I'm not David I'm not a
but if I were I'm put my money on Hooper
moving on from heavy people to heavy
mugs all right Alo set the internet on
fire by releasing a really heavy coffee
mug right sold out there were back
orders and like people had trouble
getting there it crashed the website
caus all this it caused a lot of earned
press for a Leo is what is there were a
few snafus but hey all publicity is good
publicity especially when you're making
heavy
things Rogue
Fitness they have fired back Phil how
have they fired back they fired back by
releasing a nearly
$500 3 week to get in shipping 20
kilogram coffee mug that literally looks
like you you're pulling a bullet out of
a
canteen this is heavy it is large it is
expensive and it is awesome and it is
sold out by the way it's sold out so
wait so quick way sold out do you want
one sorry you're not getting one do do
you know do you see you see this mug
this mug looks like a normal mug it's
cuz it's not cool it's not heavy it's
not $500 so this is like twice as heavy
as a Lego's mug but I want to be clear
here it's like a build weight right in
wrestling right and then like the actual
weight it's build weight it's 20
kilograms actual weight is about half
that because the artillery head the top
of the bullet the Warhead if you will is
like half the weight and you you
actually have to take it off if you want
to drink coffee out of it so you could
like keep that on to keep your coffee
nice and piping hot maybe but you take
that off it's like half the we it's more
akin to ao's mug maybe still a little
bit heavier I don't know we have to do
like a gram Byram analysis I just do
want to say this is the most American
thing I've ever heard because it's like
oh a Swedish company's doing something
double it USA that is very much the EOS
Rogue is taking into this they actually
and I quote here's a comment that Rogue
had Sorry by the way I called it the
artillery mug it's the Anvil mug the
Anvil mug it just looks like an
artillery shell so of course I called it
that Rogue said in comparing their mug
to alos the two mugs really aren't on
the same level our Anvil mug is a true
work of art shots fired I'm just waiting
for the response we're going to see
Noble come out with the Bazooka mug and
it's go it's going be go cuz they're
doing the crossing go Ro go Ro yeah go
rock with the Bazooka muger I I'm just
waiting for the first time where there
is a strongman contest at the Rogue
Invitational which is drink chug chug a
coffee from the Anvil mug okay and it's
gonna gock if you're listening to this
you want some something free cool a
weighted ruck sack mug you have to put
on the ruck sack in order to drink the
it's attached and you it's like a full
way to think you can have that that's
free that's free that's free ideas are
free my ideas are free sometimes the
next Rogue record
breaker uh I do want to give a shout out
and we will link it in a card here
roughly I'm kind of bad sometimes at
time in the cards and probably in the
description below if I remember our
buddy Cooper over at garage gym reviews
our sister site did get his hands on the
ELO M put an aw put up an awesome video
on it and uh dude looks good on camera
can he drink from a 20 pound mug you'll
have to see you have to see for yourself
anywh who we're not done talking about
strong people yet because we're going to
go back to the world of strong man Hur
bjornson aka the
mountain who has some uh IMDb credits
via that their Game of Thrones and other
things he's getting back in a strong man
he won World's Strongest Man then didn't
defend the title partially because he
hurt his foot par because Martin's leas
he's had a great year shout out to
martines then he deadlifted 51 kilg to
beat Eddie Hall and then he took up
boxing and then he literally beat Eddie
Hall in the ring then he got the
powerlifting and then he got injured and
now he's getting back into strongman
what did H how's H's training looking
Phil so his training is actually looking
pretty good so the reason that we're
covering him in his Arnold Classic prep
is because he in in training at least he
deadlifted 440 kilograms on an elephant
bar now the elephant the rogue elephant
bar is that long bar with a lot of whip
that's used pretty much exclusively at
the Arnold Classic
and 440 is pretty impressive for a guy
who hasn't been in the strong man game
for several years he actually has three
Arnold strongman classic titles and he's
got the rogue elephant bar deadlift
world record at 474 kilograms he lifted
440 he calls his shot that he's going to
lift 460 at the Arnold so I don't know
if I if in my return I want to give my
competition the Target that they should
also be preparing for but if he can
score 460 after being out of the game
that's only 14 kilograms off the world
record 4 40 is pretty impressive in
training 460 would be very impressive on
competition day 474 is the record so
we'll see if anybody tries to challenge
that but yeah Hur beon getting back to
the game it looks like he's going to do
pretty good and hopefully he can make me
shut my mouth and he podiums and looks
really strong I just want to point out
haur Bon not someone we will be seeing I
mean I guess stranger things have
happened but like I wouldn't bet on it
not someone we're going to be seeing at
World's Strongest Man basically we'll
see him at the Arnold don't expect to
see him at World's Strongest Man bile
accounts not on the best turn terms with
that competition basically yeah the
whole the whole I mean the quick rundown
I mean the reason that Eddie Hall and
and uh haor got into the you know into
fisticuffs in the ring in the first
place the reason that that built up and
the you know the fight for the heaviest
deadlift of all time is because they
competed at the 2017 world strongest man
there was a may or may not you be the
judge call on a final rep for haor bejon
that would have given him the title over
Hedy Hall that year so there was
controversy surrounding that and then a
rivalry between those two guys like
built up and pent up and then the next
year hawthor wins in 2018 but Eddie did
not compete because he was done after
2017 when he won and then came out with
some more shots fired saying that he
would have H only won because Eddie
didn't compete you know more smack talk
back and forth and eventually they were
like hey the world wants to see us fight
so then they fought but then haor won so
you know the last time they competed
against each other and strongman Eddie
won but then when they actually got into
the ring haor won and then you know
Eddie got his Haw Thor's name tattooed
on his foot because they made a bet
about that fight and then that also
stirred some cont there's a lot there's
a lot but all that is to say hawor maybe
not on the best terms with giants live
but maybe they can reconcile and we
could see him return to the world's
strongest man competition if he does
really well at the Arnold strongman
classic stranger things have happened
but he does theoretically have a
lifetime invite to the World's Strongest
Man as a former Champion lck going on
there lock going on there let's let's go
to a sport that has no politics I'm
joking because it has Pol all strength
Sports have politics string Sports is
politics and that's powerlifting Great
Britain's own Tony Cliff 120 kilogram
powerlifter two time world champion
looking pretty good heading into the
Sheffield which is on home turf for him
in February Phil how good is he looking
especially in the bench press and I
would I would do like a bench press
motion but I'm like sitting in a chair
and it's just it's going to look like a
weird shoulder prep I'm just not gonna
do it yeah I mean well Tony Cliff is not
doing weird shoulder presses for sure
because uh he looks he looks looking
damn good leading up to the Sheffield
which going to take place on February
10th uh he posted a training lift of 2
and a half kilograms over the current
bench press world record in his weight
class now the Sheffield it's a little
bit different from other powerlifting
contests where it's an invitation only
meet and athletes are going to be scored
based on the proportion of World Records
in their weight class that they're
competing in so it maximizes everybody's
uh incentive to lift as heavy as they
can regardless of how anybody else is
lifting around them and Tony cliff and a
bunch of other the athletes that are
going to be competing there have been
looking really really strong in training
like I feel like we have covered more
unofficial records in the buildup to the
2024 Sheffield than we ever have before
and we cover a lot of training lifts and
Tony Cliffs happens to be one of the
more impressive among amongst them
because it did not look like it was a
difficult lift for him to go two and a
half kilos over the current world record
so fully expect him to call for a world
record in one of his attempts at the
Sheffield and potentially post that
prize and then win the 5,000 that come
along with any world record broken in an
not 5,000 it's 5,000 pound
p6400 as of this recording so yes you
get you get a nice little kicker there
for setting a world record and he did
Ben for us in training 255.50 kilos we
don't know what his body weight was
right this wasn't after like his Squad
attempts or anything like that we don't
know of but 255.50 kilos are about 563
pounds more than a tick above the world
record in in his body weight division so
you know I do think that he's kind of
he's kind of giving us a preview and he
saying hey you know I'm I'm probably
going for this record Tony Cliff one of
the world's best powerlifters probably
not as well known in the United States
as he is in the UK and I think he will
probably use that to advant his
Advantage lifting on home turf there and
being more of a known quantity among or
within the UK powerlifting scene so I'm
excited to see Tony lift uh I like
watching him lift you always want to see
the hometown hero not Hometown but Home
Country hero do well um but H sff
competition because there is a lot of
lifters looking for those top prizes you
can walk away people can walk away with
like mid five figures depending on how
they stack like how they've done it
overall with some World Records like you
can walk away with you know $50,000 plus
us yeah I'm sure a bunch of the athletes
that are going to compete at the
Sheffield are going in expecting it to
be the largest Payday for them
throughout the year like more and more
this is becoming like the Super Bowl of
powerlifting in a way it's like the
world championships and now Sheffield
but like Sheffield just because of the
clout and the elevated elevation of like
all of these athletes competing with the
incentive to go as heavy as they
possibly can and the money the price
money to back it up so I expect to see a
lot of big things from uh at the
Sheffield and Tony Cliff bench pressing
a world record is like just the the
floor of what I think we're going to see
very much so excited about that probably
the most exciting probably the most
excited I am for a power lifting
competition this year and feel sadly the
bummer is that brings us to the end of
this strength weekly but wow it's been
popping off popping off with training
lifts popping off with MMA preparation
popping off with heavy mugs what will
the world bring next week well from the
folks bringing you everything around the
barbell game bar band.com I'm David
Thomas to joined by Phil bman thank you
for joining us I have to go put in my uh
weight listed uh order for an anvil mug
that I won't be able to lift and I
appreciate all of you uh supporting me
on that Journey cheers
[Music]
folks